...the scars run deep.
Heartbreak Ridge is a war, drama film directed by Clint Eastwood.
A hard-nosed, hard-living Marine gunnery sergeant clashes with his superiors and his
ex-wife as he takes command of a spoiled recon platoon with a bad attitude.
Gunnery Sgt. Tom 'Gunny' Highway, played by Clint Eastwood.
Aggie, played by Marsha Mason.
Major Malcolm A. Powers, played by Everett McGill.
Staff Sergeant Webster, played by Moses Gunn.
Corporal 'Stitch' Jones, played by Mario Van Peebles.
Little Mary Jackson, played by Eileen Heckart.
Heartbreak Ridge is a 1986 American war film directed,
produced by, and starring Clint Eastwood.
The film co-stars Marsha Mason, Everett McGill, and Mario Van Peebles,
and was released in the United States on December 5, 1986.
The story centers on a U.S.
Marine nearing retirement who gets a platoon of undisciplined Marines into shape
and leads them during the American invasion of Grenada in 1983.
The title comes from the Battle of Heartbreak Ridge in the Korean War, in
which Eastwood's character had been awarded the Medal of Honor.
The film explores themes of war veteran, patriotism,
recruit, battle assignment, marine.
The tone is emotional.